was the function. Now, you may say
say well it's obvious wasn't always obvious.
obvious. The idea of a function of a as an
as an abstraction did not come about until thethe 1940s 1950s
And even then it was considered to be
be an astonishingly
controversial idea. Why is that the case?
case because every time you do a function call it
All it requires two or three more
instructions and those were in the days of
of computing back then, extremely
expensive. So we had this this
This tradeoff between do we build things
that serve our machines do we build
build things that serve the needs of our humans.
I was at this battle, but in those
In those days, the machines were far more
more expensive than our humans, and so a lot of what we happen in
happened in software engineering was to optimize the needs for the
for the machine, not the humans themselves.
yourselves. Well, with
With the advent of micro-miniaturization, we had from the mainframe
mainframes, we suddenly had many
minicomputers like the PDP-11
oven uh 60 series uh we had
microcomputers as well